Paul Toner

Washington, D.C. | Portfolio | Github | (720) 276-1928 | paul@paulyprograms.com

SUMMARY

A customer-service professional of 10+ years, I developed teamwork, leadership, and communication skills, and... I know what it's like to be the new guy, from multiple professional experiences. I know the grind it takes to earn the respect of my peers and superiors. This will all be demonstrated in an **entry level software development role** at a company that values career development for its junior engineers.

SKILLS

Frameworks: React, Next, EJS, Styled-Components, Express, Material UI / Emotion

Languages: Javascript, CSS / SCSS, HTML, Node.is

Database: Mongo DevOps: Git

Cloud Platforms: AWS code deployment

WORK EXPERIENCE

El Five Restaurant, Denver, CO Server | January 2020 - June 2022

Demonstrated leadership as a captain and trainer for new employees for 1.5 years

Frasca Food and Wine, Boulder, CO

Server | September 2017 - December 2019

Demonstrated versatility by performing 6 different roles in the front of house Won the 2019 James Beard Award for Service as part of a 15-person team

Finalist for the 2018 James Beard Award for Best Restaurant as part of a 15-person team

EDUCATION

Howard Community College Columbia, MD, Finance 2011-2013
The Web Developer Bootcamp Udemy Colt Steele August 2022
The Modern React Bootcamp Udemy Colt Steele September 2022
Advanced CSS and SASS Course Udemy Jonas Schmedtmann October 2022

PROJECTS

sort-spotify.com | Github Repository

January 2023 - Present

Full-stack web site that allows the user to sort through their "Liked Songs" playlist from Spotify and save the results as a new playlist in their account. Spotify does not yet provide this feature, and this website is likely the only in existence that does so.

- 3 monthly users
- 897 lines of React front end
- 285 lines of Express back end
- 1417 lines of custom CSS using the styled-components library / CSS in JS

paulyprograms.com | Github Repository

January 2023 - Present

Front-end focused showcase that features screen-recorded videos that walk the viewer through the functionality of other notable projects with commentary about the engineering process.

- 864 lines of React
- 1132 lines of custom SASS